<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Go - Category - Mtlmacedo.com</title>
        <link>https://mtlmacedo.com/categories/go/</link>
        <description>Go - Category - Mtlmacedo.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mtlmacedo@gmail.com (Matheus Macedo)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mtlmacedo@gmail.com (Matheus Macedo)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 13:45:56 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mtlmacedo.com/categories/go/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Poiters: Understanding Value vs. Reference in Go</title>
    <link>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/poiters/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 13:45:56 -0300</pubDate>
    <author>Matheus Macedo</author>
    <guid>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/poiters/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Continuing our Go programming 101 series:
Today we&rsquo;re going to discuss a fascinating topic that is relevant to almost all programming languages: value vs. reference (also known as pointers).
First and foremost, let&rsquo;s remember that every variable we create, regardless of its type, as well as arrays, slices, and maps, are allocated in memory.
Another crucial point to bear in mind is that function parameters are also variables.
To help us understand this concept better, let&rsquo;s create a function with two parameters.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Go Programming 101: Arrays, Slices and Maps</title>
    <link>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/lists/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:03:15 -0300</pubDate>
    <author>Matheus Macedo</author>
    <guid>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/lists/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Go lang: Arrays, Slices, and Maps Explained Welcome to another exciting installment of our GO 101 series! Today we&rsquo;ll delve into arrays, slices, and maps. These data structures are fundamental in Go and mastering them will greatly enhance your development skills. So let&rsquo;s dive right in!
Arrays In Go, an array is a fixed-size sequence of elements of the same type. They provide a way to store and access multiple values under a single name.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Go Programming 101: A Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
    <link>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/gobasics/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 15:03:15 -0300</pubDate>
    <author>Matheus Macedo</author>
    <guid>https://mtlmacedo.com/posts/gobasics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Welcome to the exciting world of Go programming! In this blog post, we will explore why Go has become increasingly popular and discuss its unique features and benefits. Whether you&rsquo;re a beginner looking to dive into programming or an experienced developer curious about Go, this guide will provide you with a solid foundation to start your Go journey.
Why Go is gaining popularity Go has been making waves in the programming community due to its remarkable features and advantages.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
